institutionalinvestor.com 2007-12-10

# Euromoney Institutional Investor- Privacy Policy

Euromoney Institutional Investor PLC and Institutional Investor Inc

PRIVACY STATEMENT 

Our Privacy Commitments 

Euromoney Institutional Investor plc and Institutional Investor Inc. (together, "Euromoney") respect the privacy of every person who visits, registers with or subscribes to our websites and on-line publications, and is committed to ensuring a safe on-line experience. This Privacy Statement applies to all Euromoney’s websites ("Sites") as listed below under the heading "Sites" and outlines the information Euromoney may collect and how we may use that information. This Privacy Statement also tells you how you can verify the accuracy of your personal information submitted to Euromoney through our Sites and how you can request that we delete or update it. 

This Privacy Statement consists of a general section, which applies to all Sites, followed by specific sections on Euromoney.com and Euromoneyplc.com Sites that provide supplementary information about the personal information collected on those Sites. 

For the purpose of this Privacy Statement "group company" shall mean Euromoney Institutional Investor plc and any of its subsidiary companies, including, without limitation, Institutional Investor Inc. 

Please note that the Sites may contain links to external sites and may contain advertisements for, and/or the opportunity for you to purchase products or services from third parties. Please note that this privacy statement does not control the activities of such third parties, and users should consult those third party sites' privacy policies. 

**Information about Euromoney** Euromoney’s principal business activities are: 

• Business-to-Business Financial Publishing   
• Organisers of Seminars, Conferences, Training Courses and Exhibitions for the financial markets industry 

Euromoney Institutional Investor plc Company Address:  
Nestor House,  
Playhouse Yard,  
London EC4V 5EX  
United Kingdom 

Institutional Investor, Inc. Company Address:  
225 Park Ave. South,   
New York,   
NY 10003,   
USA 

**  
Name of the Data Controller** The Data Controller is Euromoney Institutional Investor plc, and, in relation to our US Sites (as listed below under "Sites"), Institutional Investor Inc. is also a Data Controller. 

Euromoney Institutional Investor plc is subject to the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and is registered in the UK with the Information Commissioner to process your personal information. **

Collection of Personal Information

** Euromoney’s primary goal in collecting personal information from you is to give you an enjoyable customised experience whilst allowing us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs. 

Euromoney gives you the option to access our Sites' home pages without subscribing or registering or disclosing your personal data. 

We collect certain personal information from you, which you give to us when using our Sites andor registering or subscribing for our products and services. 

We also collect certain personal data from other group companies to whom you have given information through their websites (including, by way of example, Euromoney Institutional Investor plc and Institutional Investor Inc., in accordance with the purposes listed below). 

Where, as part of our Site services, we enable you to post information or materials on our Site, we may access and monitor any information which you upload or input, including in any password-protected sections, in order to fulfil our obligations to you and protect or comply with our legal rights and obligations. 

We do not collect information about our Site visitors or online registered users or subscribers from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations. 

Please note that we do not collect any personal information from children under thirteen years of age and that no child under thirteen should submit any personal information to any of the Sites. Should we discover that any such personal information has been delivered to any of the Sites, we will remove that information as soon as possible. 

**Types of Personal Information Held and its Use  
**  
At some Sites, Euromoney collects personally identifiable information, such as your name, job title, work and/or home address, and telephone number and email address and comments/information you may input or post. At other Sites, Euromoney may collect demographic information, such as your postcode, age, gender, purchasing preferences and interests. Some Sites may collect a combination of the two types of information. 

Euromoney collects and uses your personal information to operate its Sites efficiently and to deliver the products and services you have requested. 

Your personal information may be used for the purposes of: 

• Customer Administration, i.e. part of the personal data is used for the provision of information, communications, or transaction services such as placing an order and delivering products and/or services to you.   
• Marketing, i.e. parts of your personal data may be used by Euromoney and/or its other group companies to contact you by email, fax, telephone and/or post for sending information or promotional material on the products and/or services of Euromoney and/or its other group companies. 

Euromoney gives you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving marketing communications and will in certain circumstances need to obtain your consent before sending such communications to you. Further detail can be found on the applicable Site and in each marketing communication sent by Euromoney. 

• Trading in Personal Data, i.e. parts of your personal data may be collected and processed with the intention of selling it to other organisations, but only after consent has been given by you. 

Euromoney may also use your information to measure what area users visit most frequently and what information users access the most. We use this data in connection with the design of our website. This information also helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users and how we can continually create a better overall service for you. Employees or contractors of Euromoney who are given access to your 

usage information will be required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for Euromoney.

Any other purposes for which Euromoney wishes to use your personal data will be notified to you and your personal data will not be used for any such purpose without obtaining your prior consent. 

Further detail as to the types of personal information which are collected at Euromoney.com and Euromoneyplc.com is set out at the end of this Privacy Statement. 

**  
Consents and opt-outs** You can give your consent to or opt-out of particular uses of your data as indicated above by:   
• Indicating in a box at the point on the relevant Site where personal data is collected;   
• Informing Euromoney by email, post or phone; or  
• Updating your preferences on the applicable Site. 

**  
Use of Cookies** All Euromoney 's Site’s use "cookies". 

A cookie is a text file placed on your hard drive by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. They are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie. 

Cookies are either used only during your session (“temporary” or "session state" cookies) or stored on your computers hard drive (“permanent” cookies). 

Temporary cookies are a mechanism for maintaining continuity between pages during your visit. These cookies are maintained in your browser’s active memory and are terminated at the conclusion of the Site visit. Permanent cookies are used to recall on subsequent visits your login information and your agreement to our terms and conditions. 

Cookies are integral to the functioning of all Euromoney Sites. By using your browser’s options to block cookies you will effectively prohibit effective use of Euromoney sites. If you still wish to control the operation of cookies, then functionality is available through your browser. Generally you have the options to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is issued or reject all cookies. Below are instructions on controlling cookies in the most recent version of Windows Explorer (Users of other browsers should contact their manufacturer for instructions). 

Windows Internet Explorer 6.x   
Select Tools Internet Options then Privacy Tab then Advanced  
Check Override automatic cookie handling  
Click Accept, Block or Prompt then OK twice 

As outlined above, disabling cookies may prevent Euromoney Sites from operating fully. **

Disclosures

** Information collected at one Site may be shared within Euromoney and other group companies for the purposes listed above. 

Your personal data may also be sold to other companies in the form of lists and directories, but only after permission from you in accordance with the provisions above. 

Euromoney may also disclose your personal data to third parties, including, without limitation, professional advisers, or governmental or State institutions or authorities, where necessary in order to exercise or defend its legal rights or where required by law. 

Please note that the Sites may contain links to external sites and may contain advertisements for, and/or the opportunity for you to purchase products or services from third parties. Please note that this privacy statement does not control the activities of such third parties, and users should consult those third party sites' privacy policies.  If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: <http://www.advertising.com/Privacy.html>

**Transfers outside the EEA** Euromoney may transfer your personal data, for the purposes listed above, to other group companies or other third parties which may be located in countries outside the European Economic Area, whose laws are not recognised by the EU Commission as providing adequate level of protection to personal data. This will include transfers to Institutional Investor, Inc. in the US. **

Confidentiality Security of Your Personal Information

** Euromoney is committed to keeping the data you provide us secure and will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. 

We have implemented information security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from: 

• unauthorised access   
• improper use or disclosure   
• unauthorised modification   
• unlawful destruction or accidental loss 

All our employees and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal data on our behalf, for the purposes listed above), who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our Site visitors' personal data. 

We also give you the option of using a secure transmission method to send us personal data identifiers, such as credit card details and bank account number. 

How to Access, Update and Erase your Personal Information 

If you wish to know whether we are keeping personal data about you, or if you have an enquiry about our privacy policy or your personal information held by Euromoney, in relation to all the Sites whether run by Euromoney Institutional Investor Plc or Institutional Investor Inc., you can contact the Data Protection Officer via: 

• Postal mail to this address : Data Protection Officer, Euromoney Institutional Investor plc, Nestor House, Playhouse Yard, London EC4V 5EX, UK  
•  Telephone: +44 (0)20 7779 8600   
•  Email: [dataprotectionofficer@euromoneyplc.com](mailto:dataprotectionofficer@euromoneyplc.com "mailto:dataprotectionofficer@euromoneyplc.com")

Upon request, we will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you. We may require proof of your identity and may charge a small fee to cover administration and postage. 

Euromoney allows you to challenge the data that we hold about you and, where appropriate in accordance with applicable laws, you may have your personal information: 

• erased   
• rectified or amended   
• completed 

**Changes to this Privacy Statement** Euromoney will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect new legislation or industry practice, group company changes and customer feedback. We encourage you to review this Privacy Statement periodically to be informed of how Euromoney is protecting your personal information. 

**Sites** This Privacy Statement applies to the websites located on the World Wide Web , including but not limited to, the following domains: 

Euromoney Institutional Investor plc Sites

absolutereturn.net business-missions.co.uk euromoneybooks.com  
absolutereturnmagazine.com business-missions.com euromoneychina.com  
adhes.com chinalawandpractice.com euromoneyconf.co.uk  
adhesion.co.uk chinalawpractice.com euromoneyconferences.co.uk  
africahedge.com chinamoney.com.hk euromoneydata.com  
aircrafteconomics.co.uk coalconferences.co.uk euromoneydigital.com  
aircrafteconomics.com coalconferences.com euromoneydirectory.com  
aircraftevents.com coaltrans.com euromoneyenergy.com  
airfinanceconferences.com coaltransconferences.co.uk euromoneyhk.com  
airfinancejournal.co.uk coaltransconferences.com euromoneyii.com  
airfinancejournal.com contractcommunications.com euromoneyii.net  
airfinancejournal.net corporatefinancefx.com euromoneyinstitutionalinvestorplc.com  
airtrafficmanagement.net cruiseandferryreview.com euromoneyinvestorshows.com  
allaboutports.com dcgardner.com euromoneyleasetraining.com  
alphk.com dcgardnertraining.co.uk euromoneylegaltraining.com  
americahedge.com dcgardnertraining.com euromoney-magazine.com  
anenglishsummer.com dcgcredittraining.com euromoneypharmaevents.com  
asiahedge.biz dcgtraining.co.uk euromoneyplc.co.uk  
asiahedge.co.uk dutyfreenews.co.uk euromoneyplc.com  
asiahedge.com dutyfreenews.com euromoneyplc.net  
asiahedge.info efdreview.com euromoneyplc.org  
asiahedge.net emconferences.co.uk euromoneypolska.pl  
asiahedge.org emergingmarkets.org Euromoneypropinvest.com  
asialaw.com emwebtraining.com euromoney-propinvest.com  
asialawandpractice.com equitycongress.com euromoneysecure.com  
asiamoney.com euroconferences.co.uk euromoneyseminars.com  
asiamoney.com.hk eurohedge.biz euromoneytraining.co.uk  
assetfinance.co.uk eurohedge.co.uk euromoneytransport.com  
assetfinance.com eurohedge.com euromoney-yearbooks.co.uk  
assetfinanceconferences.com eurohedge.info euromoney-yearbooks.net  
atmevents.com eurohedge.net euroweek.co.uk  
batteriesint.com eurohedge.org euroweek.com  
batteriesinternational.co.uk euroinvestmagazine.com euroweekhk.com  
batteriesinternational.com euromoney.co.uk ew-sfi.com  
bondcongress.com euromoneyasia.com   
business-meetings.co.uk euromoneybooks.co.uk   
expertguides.co.uk internal-audit.org peoplemoves.co.uk  
expertguides.com internationalglassreview.com peoplemoves.com  
forexforum.co.uk investhedge.biz perrypublications.co.uk  
gimagazine.com investhedge.co.uk perrypublications.com  
globalagendamagazine.com investhedge.com petroleumeconomist.co.uk  
globalborrower.co.uk investhedge.info petroleum-economist.co.uk  
globalborrowers.com investhedge.net petroleumeconomist.com  
globalinvestormagazine.com investhedge.org pharmalive.com  
globalpoliticalrisk.com investment-banking-operations.com politicalriskmap.com  
globaltelecomsbusiness.co.uk ipprofiles.com prcmoney.net  
globaltelecomsbusiness.com is-audit.org projectfinance.co.uk  
Hedgefundintelligence.biz isfmagazine.com project-tradefinance.co.uk  
hedgefundintelligence.co.uk islamicfinancesummit.com railfinanceinternational.com  
hedgefundintelligence.com islamicfinanceweekly.com Ravenfox.co.uk  
Hedgefundintelligence.info italiahedge.com Ravenfox.com  
Hedgefundintelligence.net it-audit.org ravenfoxhorizon.com  
hedgefundintelligence.org limitedpartnerscongress.com reactionawards.co.uk  
hedgemagazine.com limited-partnerscongress.com reactions.co.uk  
iflr.co.uk managingip.co.uk reactions.org  
iflr.com media.euromoneydigital.com reactionsawards.co.uk  
iflr1000.co.uk mipweek.com reactionsawards.com  
iflr1000.com misti.com reactionsawards.net  
iflrasia.com mistiemea.com reactionsnet.com  
iflrgraduates.com mistieurope.com reinsurancelaw.com  
iflrweek.com mistraining.com reinsurance-training.com  
iiassetmanagers.com mis-training.com re-insurance-training.com  
iicapital.com mistraining.net rfh-insight.com  
ii-conferences.com mis-training.net russiamoney.net  
iidestinations.com mistraining.org screen-news.com  
iifamilyoffice.com mis-training.org selfstudysolutions.co.uk  
iifasttrack.com nipponhedge.biz selfstudysolutions.com  
iihedge.com nipponhedge.com seniortravel.co.uk  
iihongkong.com nipponhedge.info sfidata.net  
iijournals.com nipponhedge.net sfidirectory.com  
iilondon.com nipponhedge.org sfinews.net  
iimemberships.com officeproductsawards.com shipfinanceinternational.com  
Iinewslts.com opi.co.uk southafricahedge.com  
iiplansponsors.com opi.net sponsors.euromoney.com  
iiresearchgroup.co.uk opiasia.net sportsfinance.net  
iiseminars.com Opichina.net strategicdirectinvestor.co.uk  
insecuritization.com opi-mag.com taxreviewweek.com  
inssecuritisation.com opinet.com techlawlive.com  
inssecuritization.com outsourcing-assetmanagers.com telecomsmoney.com  
insurancebooks.com outsourcingcongress.com telecoms-online.com  
insuranceconferences.com outsourcing-congress.com tradefinanceconferences.com  
insurancemoves.com outsourcinginvestmentbanks.com tradefinancemagazine.co.uk  
insurancesecuritisation.com outsourcing-investmentbanks.com transportmagazines.com  
travelretailer.co.uk travelretailerworld.com usinsurer.com  
travelretailer.com travelretailworld.com vinisud.com  
travelretailerinternational.com Ushedge.com 

Institutional Investor Inc. Sites, including but not limited to, the following domains: 

alternativeinvestmentnews.com fundmarketing.com iisearches.com  
bondweek.com globalfundnews.com iitechfinance.com  
businesstravelerusa.com globalmoneymanagement.com iiwealthmanagement.com  
compliancereporter.com gulfpub.com institutionalinvestor.net  
compositecatalog.com hpboxscore.com institutionalinvestoronline.com  
constructionboxscore.com iialternatives.com loanmarketweek.com  
corporatefinancingweek.com iicorporatefinance.com moneymanagementletter.com  
dcnews.com iihighnetworth.com operationsmanagement.com  
derivativesweek.com iijpm.com pipe-line.com  
euromoney.net iimarketplace.com securitizationnews.com  
financialnetnews.com iinow.com telecomfinancingweek.com  
fintechforum.com iiplatinum.com wallstreetletter.com  
foundationendowment.com iipower.com worldoil.com  
fundaction.com iirealestate.com   
funddirections.com iirenew.com 

Further detail as to the information which is collected at Euromoney.com and Euromoneyplc.com is set out below. 

**General Information** Personal data from the above listed websites which is held by Euromoney. 

Below is a table of personal data collected and the purposes for which it may be used. 

**Data Classes**

| 

   **Advertising, Marketing & Public Relations**

| 

   **Accounts & Records**

| 

   **Administration of Membership Records**

| 

   **Advertising Marketing & Public Relations for others**

| 

   **Education**

| 

   **Information & Databank Administration**

| 

   **Journalism and Media**

| 

   **Research**

| 

   **Trading/sharing in Personal Information**  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
Personal Details

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X  
  
Family, Lifestyle and Social Circumstances

| 

X

|  |  | 

X

|  | 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X  
  
Education and Training Details

| 

X

|  |  | 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X  
  
Employment Details

| 

X

|  |  |  |  | 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X  
  
Financial Details

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X  
  
Goods or Services Provided

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X

| 

X
